The award winning musical comes to the screen!
1776 is a drama, history film directed by Peter H. Hunt.
Colonial representatives gather in Philadelphia with the aim of establishing a
set of governmental rules for the burgeoning United States.
Benjamin Franklin and John Adams charge Thomas Jefferson with the task of writing a
statement announcing the new country's emancipation from British rule.
John Adams, played by William Daniels.
Dr. Benjamin Franklin, played by Howard Da Silva.
Thomas Jefferson, played by Ken Howard.
Martha Jefferson, played by Blythe Danner.
John Dickinson (PA), played by Donald Madden.
Edward Rutledge (SC), played by John Cullum.
1776 is a 1972 American historical musical drama film directed by Peter H.
Hunt and written by Peter Stone, based on his book for the 1969 Broadway
musical of the same name, with music and lyrics by Sherman Edwards.
Set in Philadelphia in the summer of 1776, it is a fictionalized account of the
events leading up to the signing of the Declaration of Independence.
The film stars William Daniels, Howard da Silva, Donald
Madden, John Cullum, Ken Howard and Blythe Danner.
Portions of dialogue and some lyrics were taken directly from the letters and
memoirs of the actual participants of the Second Continental Congress.
The film explores themes of philadelphia, pennsylvania, congress,
musical, based on true story, based on play or musical.
The tone is emotional.